

# HOLLY HILLIARD

WRITER

## **EDUCATION**

#### **North Carolina State University**

MFA in Creative Writing, 2019

- Taught undergraduate Intro to Fiction Writing (3 sections).
- Won the Robbie S. Knott Scholarship in Fiction Writing.
- Won the James Hurst Prize for Fiction.

## **Duke University**

BA in English, minor in music, 2013

- Earned Highest Distinction in Creative Writing.
- Graduated Summa Cum Laude and a member of Phi Beta Kappa Honors Society.

## **VOLUNTEERING**

#### **Humane Animal Rescue**

Nursery Volunteer, March 2024-Present

#### **Three Rivers Birding Club**

Social Media Coordinator, Nov. 2023 - Present

## **Feminist Bird Club of Madison**

Engagement Committee Member, March 2022 - May 2023

## **SKILLS**

- Applications: Microsoft Office Suite, G-Suite products, Zoom
- CRM & Marketing: ZenDesk, Guru, MailChimp, Substack
- Design Programs: Adobe Creative Suite, Canva

#### CONTACT



hilliardwrites@gmail.com



Pittsburgh, PA



hollyhilliard.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

I'm a detail-oriented proponent of the Oxford comma with over 12 years of professional writing and editing experience. From customerfacing explanations of legal policies and procedures to government grants for arts nonprofits, I've written materials for a wide range of industries and clients. Since 2021, I've worked as a freelance editor, writer, and educator while also completing a novel and a short story collection. I am deeply organized, conscientious, and self-motivated.

#### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Grant Writer**

Aug. 2024-Present

Film Pittsburgh (Pittsburgh, PA)

- Applied for over \$1 million in grant funding from private foundations and government entities in 6 months.
- Track grant progress and write final reports.
- Write and edit donor solicitations, press releases, op-eds, program guides, website posts, and sponsorship materials.

## **Adult Arts Instructor**

Aug. 2021-Present

Madison School and Community Recreation (Madison, WI)

- Teach and develop curriculum for creative writing courses geared toward adults in the community.
- Use a variety of instructional methods, including both Zoom and in-person classes, group workshops, in-class writing, critical reading, group discussion, and peer-to-peer feedback.

## **Legal Operations Manager**

Nov. 2016-Aug. 2021

Etsy, Inc. (Brooklyn, NY)

- Wrote and managed all internal- and external-facing documentation for the Legal Response & Enforcement Team, including Standard Operating Procedures, ~200 customer-facing email templates, and articles on help.etsy.com that averaged 44,000 views each per year.
- Responded to legal complaints and customer service inquiries. Worked with attorneys general, law enforcement agencies, and the BBB to handle concerns on Etsy.com.
- Developed a 4-week New Hire Training curriculum and led individual and group training sessions over video.

#### **Literary Assistant**

Jan. 2014-July 2016

Sterling Lord Literistic, Inc. (New York, NY)

- Read and edited client manuscripts and prepared materials for submission to publishing houses.
- Managed day-to-day needs of over 250 active clients.
- Drafted licenses for third-party use of clients' material and sold subsidiary rights to clients' books.